Cute. Clever. Mischievous. Intelligent. Dangerous.
Gremlins is a fantasy, horror, comedy film directed by Joe Dante.
After receiving an exotic small animal as a Christmas gift, a young man inadvertently breaks three important rules
concerning his new pet, which unleashes a horde of malevolently mischievous creatures on a small town.
Billy Peltzer, played by Zach Galligan.
Kate Beringer, played by Phoebe Cates.
Randall Peltzer, played by Hoyt Axton.
Lynn Peltzer, played by Frances Lee McCain.
Pete Fountaine, played by Corey Feldman.
Grandfather (Mr. Wing), played by Keye Luke.
Gremlins is a 1984 American black comedy horror film directed by Joe Dante, written by Chris Columbus and starring Zach Galligan,
Phoebe Cates, Hoyt Axton, Polly Holliday and Frances Lee McCain, with Howie Mandel providing the voice of Gizmo the Mogwai.
It draws on legends of folkloric mischievous creatures that cause
malfunctions—"gremlins"—in the British Royal Air Force going back to World War II.
The story follows Billy Peltzer, who receives Gizmo as a pet, who then spawns more of his kind that evolve
into the titular imp-like monsters that wreak havoc on Billy's hometown during Christmas Eve.
The film was accompanied by a large merchandising campaign and
juxtaposes black comedy with a Christmas time setting.
Steven Spielberg was the executive producer, with the
film being produced by Michael Finnell.
Gremlins was theatrically released on June 8, 1984, by Warner Bros.
to critical and commercial success.
However, it was heavily criticized for some of its more violent sequences.
In response to this and to similar complaints about Indiana Jones and the Temple of Doom, Spielberg suggested that the Motion Picture
Association of America (MPAA) alter its rating system, which it did within two months of the film's release, creating a new PG-13 rating.
It was followed by a sequel, Gremlins 2: The New Batch (1990), while a
third film is set to be released on November 19, 2027.
The film explores themes of small town, monster, holiday, department store, pet.
The tone is lighthearted and dark.